Some assembly required.
The Avengers is a science fiction, action,
adventure film directed by Joss Whedon.
When an unexpected enemy emerges and threatens global safety and security, Nick Fury, director of the international peacekeeping
agency known as S.H.I.E.L.D., finds himself in need of a team to pull the world back from the brink of disaster.
Spanning the globe, a daring recruitment effort begins!
Tony Stark / Iron Man, played by Robert Downey Jr..
Steve Rogers / Captain America, played by Chris Evans.
Bruce Banner / The Hulk, played by Mark Ruffalo.
Thor, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Natasha Romanoff / Black Widow, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Clint Barton / Hawkeye, played by Jeremy Renner.
Marvel's The Avengers (titled Marvel Avengers Assemble in the United Kingdom and Ireland and commonly referred to as simply
The Avengers) is a 2012 American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics superhero team of the same name.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion
Pictures, it is the sixth film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
Written and directed by Joss Whedon, the film features an ensemble cast including Robert Downey Jr., Chris Evans, Mark Ruffalo, Chris
Hemsworth, Scarlett Johansson, and Jeremy Renner as the Avengers, alongside Tom Hiddleston, Stellan Skarsgård, and Samuel L.
In the film, Nick Fury and the spy agency S.H.I.E.L.D.
recruit Tony Stark, Steve Rogers, Bruce Banner, Thor, Natasha Romanoff, and Clint Barton to
form a team capable of stopping Thor's brother Loki from subjugating Earth.
The film's development began when Marvel Studios received
a loan from Merrill Lynch in April 2005.
After the success of the film Iron Man in May 2008, Marvel announced that The Avengers would be released in July 2011 and would bring together Stark (Downey),
Rogers (Evans), Thor (Hemsworth), and Banner (portrayed by Edward Norton in the 2008 film The Incredible Hulk) from Marvel's previous films.
After the signing of Johansson as Romanoff in March 2009, Renner as Barton in June 2010, and Ruffalo
to replace Norton as Banner in July 2010, the film was pushed back for a 2012 release.
Whedon was hired in April 2010 and rewrote the original screenplay by Zak Penn.
Production began in April 2011 in Albuquerque, New Mexico, before moving to
Cleveland, Ohio, in August and New York City in September.
The film has more than 2,200 visual effects shots.
The Avengers premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on April 11, 2012, and was
released in the United States on May 4, as the final film in Phase One of the MCU.
The film received praise for Whedon's direction and screenplay, visual
effects, action sequences, acting, and musical score.
It grossed over $1.5 billion worldwide, setting numerous box office records and becoming the
third-highest-grossing film of all time at the time of its release and the highest-grossing film of 2012.
It was the first Marvel production to generate $1 billion in ticket sales.
In 2017, The Avengers was featured as one of the 100 greatest
films of all time in an Empire magazine poll.
It received a nomination for Best Visual Effects at the 85th
Academy Awards, among numerous other accolades.
Three sequels have been released: Avengers: Age of Ultron (2015),
Avengers: Infinity War (2018), and Avengers: Endgame (2019).
The film explores themes of new york city, superhero,
shield, based on comic, alien invasion.
The tone is thought_provoking.